Yabba-Dabba-Doo!
The Flintstones is a fantasy, comedy, family film directed by Brian Levant.
Modern Stone Age family the Flintstones hit the big screen in
this live-action version of the classic cartoon.
Fred helps Barney adopt a child.
Barney sees an opportunity to repay him when Slate Mining
tests its employees to find a new executive.
But no good deed goes unpunished.
Fred Flintstone, played by John Goodman.
Wilma Flintstone, played by Elizabeth Perkins.
Barney Rubble, played by Rick Moranis.
Betty Rubble, played by Rosie O'Donnell.
Cliff Vandercave, played by Kyle MacLachlan.
Sharon Stone, played by Halle Berry.
The Flintstones is a 1994 American family comedy film
directed by Brian Levant and written by Tom S.
Parker, Jim Jennewein, and Steven E.
de Souza based on the 1960–1966 animated television
series of the same name by Hanna-Barbera.
The film stars John Goodman, Rick Moranis, Elizabeth Perkins, Rosie O'Donnell, Kyle MacLachlan,
Halle Berry, and Elizabeth Taylor (in her final theatrical film appearance).
The B-52's performed their version of the cartoon's theme song,
playing cavemen versions of themselves as the BC-52's.
In the film, after Fred Flintstone receives a promotion with the help of his friend Barney
Rubble, he becomes entangled in the nefarious schemes of his boss Cliff Vandercave.
Development of a live-action film based on The Flintstones began in 1985.
After several rejected drafts, the film rights were acquired by Amblin
Entertainment and the script was finalized in 1993.
Goodman was cast as Fred Flintstone at the insistence
of executive producer Steven Spielberg.
Filming took place in California and Utah, with physical effects provided by Jim
Henson's Creature Shop and CGI created by Industrial Light & Magic.
The Flintstones was theatrically released by Universal Pictures on May 27, 1994.
It received generally negative reviews from critics, but was a box office success,
grossing almost $342 million worldwide against a $46 million budget.
Its marketing campaign included a promotion with
McDonald's and a video game based on the film.
A prequel, The Flintstones in Viva Rock Vegas, was released in 2000.
The film explores themes of friendship, plan, jealousy, manager, adoption.
The tone is lighthearted.